

Lucas Nelaupe

Software Engineer (Android)

- 25 years old
- lucas.nelaupe@gmail.com +65 8265 4423 S lucas34990

Award-Winning mobile developer, Graduated with a Master's degree in Computer Science major in Software architecture. 3 years + experience in ANDROID and iOS development in Singapore with cross-cultural teams.

Focusing on design, performance and productivity. Working on apps to solve real world problem.

Experience

Android Software Engineer

Grab • Singapore • Full-time • Since May 2018

• Grab is Southeast Asia's leading on-demand transportation and mobile payments platform. Grab solves critical transportation challenges to make transport freedom a reality for 620 million people in Southeast Asia.

R&D mobile iOS and Android developer

V-Cube Global Services • Singapore • Full-time • Since January 2016

- Mission: Design and develop a corporate mobile chat application
 - Android full stack development (Java / Kotlin)
 - IOS backend development (Swift)
- Technical aspect
 - Swift 4, Java, Kotlin
 - Realm, SQLite, SQLCipher
 - Strong use of RxJava 2 and RxSwift
 - · Offline first app: Job scheduling, cache
- - Travis matrix and stage build
 - Keep in trying new tools, libraries and services

Android developer Intern

Massive Infinity • Singapore • Internship • March 2015 to January 2016

- Design and develop several native Android apps
 - Business intelligence app for Philippe Maurice International
 - Work management app for Singapore Technologies (ST)
- Worked back to back with the IOS team on internal apps

Community Manager

University Of Montpellier • Volunteer Work • 2015 to 2017

Merge duplicates and outdated pages

Hackathon Winner

Adullact • August 2014 to September 2014

- Crowdfunding application for Android
- Open source on Github licensed under Apache V2

Education

Master Degree: Architect, engineer of Software and web

University Of Montpellier (France) • 2013 to 2015

Compilation · Metaprogramming and reflexivity · Model-driven engineering

Bachelor degree in Computer Science

University Of Montpellier (France) • 2010 to 2013

Computer Science fundamental

Skills

Programming Languages

- Swift
- ▶ Java Kotlin
- ▶ Javascript HTML CSS



- ▶ Rx|ava
- SQLite, SQLCipher
- ▶ Junit, Robolectric
- ▶ PMD, Checkstyle, FindBugs, Error Prone, Lint, infer
- Gradle
- Android Studio

iOS

- RxSwift
- ► Realm (NoSQL database)
- XCTest
- SwiftLint, taylor, tailor
- Carthage, Swift Package Manager, Cocoapods
- ▶ AppCode

Languages

- ▶ French: Native
- ▶ English: Fluent

Interests

Sports

ADULLACT

Cycling

 Visited more than 20 countries around the world

Music

- ▶ Electronic Dance Music (EDM)
- Music festival

Open Source

- ▶ Github
- Member of Moya organisation



Grab